

gabriel.danaila.tech@gmail.com Tel: 0733.665.934 www.gabrieldanaila.com www.github.com/Gabriel-Danaila

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### Web Developer

Feb 2022 - Present

- Graduate Salesforce Commerce Cloud Developer training SFCC (feb 2024)
- Completed Web Development Bootcamp by Dr. Angela Yu's (ian 2023) and WDS Bootcamp (sept. 2022).
- · Proficient in HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, VSCode.
- · Familiar with the React framework and TypeScript.
- · Create responsive designs using Figma and Visual Studio Code.
- · Manage version control using GitHub.
- Consistently prioritise clean, modular and maintainable code to ensure optimal website performance.
- · Maintain a positive and collaborative environment with all team members.
- Stay update of the latest advancements and technologies in the field.
- Well-versed in web accessibility best practices and usability principles, continuously emphasising the importance of web best practices within the development team.
- With a strong background in troubleshooting and a natural inclination towards problem-solving, I leverage my expertise to address technical challenges promptly consistently ensuring the quality of my work.

# Mechatronics Engineer - USA, TN

Feb 2007 - Feb 2019

Nissan - Battery Manufacturing Plant for Electric Vehicles, Smyrna , TN Leviton - Warehouse and Distribution center Facilities, Lebanon, TN Cinram - Assembly Line for Warner Bros Media , La Vergne, TN

- Proficiency in operating Mitsubishi and Yamaha industrial robots at the Nissan Battery Manufacturing Plant for Electric Vehicles
- Responsible for maintaining functionality of the equipment assigned using Omron Programmable Logic Controllers software and program backups for diagnostics and troubleshooting.
- Dedicated to resolving any silent faults using software diagnostic tools.
- Tested PLC changes with tools like LogicPro simulators and performed database additions for program backups, I/O operations, equipment function checks, and circuit change proposals.
- I've actively engaged in the adoption of concepts such as Kaizen implementation, Root Cause Analysis for major Breakdown Reports, Corrective - Preventive - Predictive Maintenance, the 5S methodology designed to foster a quality work environment - Sort, Set in Order, Shine, Standardise, Sustain.
- Architect of the Standard Operation Sheet Procedure (SOS), One Point Lessons for recurring tasks, standard steps and resource identification for efficient task execution.
- Completed training in safety protocols for Lock-out/Tag-out, power tools safety and general maintenance awareness.

#### **HIGHLIGHTS**

With 15 years of experience as a Mechatronics Engineer in the USA, I have transitioned from robotics and PLC systems to a full-time Web Developer role.

I specialize in building reliable websites and applications, using the latest standards in web development.

## SKILLS

- HTML / ISML
- · CSS
- JavaScript
- Bootstrap
- React
- · Node.js
- GitHub
- Figma
- Visual Studio Code

# Work recognitions

- Emblem Plate Recognition for Work Ethics - Nissan 2013
- Best Employee Award 2012
- Perfect Attendance Award for 2011 / 2012

# **EDUCATION**

Science Degree in Engineering (SIA) Technology and Quality Control. University of Galati , 1998 – 2004

## **ABOUT ME**

I value family time and show respect and care towards those around me. I strive to maintain a peaceful vibe in all interactions, always bearing in mind that, at our core, we journey through life together.